Register of the Randall Chase Gould papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Randall Chase Gould papers
1898-1961
69086
Hoover Institution Archives
10 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 3 album boxes, 2 envelopes (12.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, clippings, and photographs relating to political and military events in the Far East, especially in China during the Sino-Japanese War of 1937-1945. Includes photographs of the Japanese bombing of Shanghai in 1937.
Gould, Randall Chase, 1898-1979.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1898 June 22 Born, Excelsior, Minnesota
1916 Graduate, Gallatin County High School, Montana
1916-1917 Student, University of Wisconsin
1923-1924 News editor, Japan Times, Tokyo, Japan
1925-1931 Bureau manager, United Press, Peking and Shanghai, China; Manila, Philippine Islands
1925-1931 News editor, Peking Daily News, Peking, China
1931-1941 Editor, Shanghai Evening Post & Mercury, Shanghai, China
1932-1949 Correspondent, Christian Science Monitor
1941 Author, Chungking Today
1943-1945 Editor, American editor, Shanghai Evening Post & Mercury
1946 Author, China in the Sun
1946-1949 President, Post-Mercury Company, Inc.
1949- Member, Editorial Staff, Denver Post, Denver, Colorado
1959-1963 Employee, The San Rafael Independent Journal
1979 Died, Mill Valley, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, clippings, and photographs relating to political and military events in the Far East, especially in China during the Sino-Japanese War of 1937-1945. Includes photographs of the Japanese bombing of Shanghai in 1937.
Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; Shanghai (China)--History.; Journalists.
- Correspondence, 1927-1958
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General, 1937-1950 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, 1937-1950
  - Bickel, Karl A., 1927-1950
  - Carpenter, Alva, C., 1954
  - Chen, Eugene, 1933-1938
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1949-1953
  - Fitch, G. A., 1937
  - Forman, Harrison, 1951
  - Fujihashi, Ichiro, 1937
  - Gannett, Lewis, 1928
  - Gould, Mr. and Mrs. George, 1943
  - Grew, Joseph C., 1945
  - Hornbeck, Stanley K., 1938
  - Howard, Roy W., 1927
  - Kuhns, Elinor, 1949
  - MacMurray, J. V. A., 1928
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1954
  - Marshall, Jim, 1938
  - Penniston, John B., 1938
  - Schnacke, Robert H., 1958
  - Soong, Norman, 1949
  - Steiner, H. Arthur, 1951
  - Sun Yat-sen, Mme. (Soong Ching-ling), 1936
  - Sung I-chung, 1938
  - Wedemeyer, Lieutenant General Albert C., 1947
- Subject File, 1898-1961
  Newspaper and magazine clippings, scrapbooks, memorabilia, and other materials, arranged chronologically or alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Associated Press releases, undated (Box 2)
  - Biographical (Box 3)
    - Memorabilia
    - Newspaper, magazine clippings, 1919-1951
    - Scrapbook, 1898-1934
    - Miscellaneous
  - Borodin, Mrs. Michael M., "How I Kept My Health and Cheerful Disposition within the Prison Walls of China through Physical Culture,", undated
  - China - Foreign Policy - Japan
  - China - History - Republic (1912-1949)
  - Collected memoranda, letters, 1927-1949
  - Miscellaneous printed matter
  - "The Occupation of Nanking." Two Accounts by Eye-Witnesses, undated (Box 4)
  - Powell, John W., 1954-1961
  - Sino-Japanese Conflict (1937-1945)
  - U.S. - Foreign Relations - China
- Speeches and Writings, 1921-1955
  Newspaper columns and articles, magazine articles, and miscellaneous drafts, arranged chronologically or alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Newspaper columns, clippings (Box 5)
    - 1922-1924
    - 1925-1926
    - 1927-1929
    - 1930-1937
    - 1938-1940
    - 1942
    - 1944
    - 1946
    - 1949-1952
    - Miscellaneous, undated
  - Titled writings, 1921-1955 (Box 6)
    - "Biographical Sketch of General Chiang Kai-shek," typewritten with handwritten insertions, 1 page
    - Book reviews, carbon and typewritten copies of book reviews by Randall Gould for the Christian Science Monitor, 1950-1953
    - "Captives of the Mikado," Far Eastern Survey, 2 printed copies, 4 pages, 1942 June 1
    - "Changing Japan," printed copy, 2 pages, undated
    - "A Chinese Warlord," The Nation, printed copy, 1 page, 1927 June 29
    - "Civil War in China Is Not Surprising," The China Digest, printed copy, 1 page, 1926 October 23
    - "Colors Change in China," printed copy, 5 pages, undated
    - "Covering the War," Leica Photography, printed copy, 2 pages, 1937 December
    - "Editor Mellen Creates a Story," printed copy of editorial, 1 page, 1921 August 30
    - "The Foreign Mentality in China," T'ien Hsia Monthly, printed copy, 14 pages, undated
    - "Foreign Views on General Chiang," The China Critic, printed copy, 2 pages, 1936 November 5
    - "A Foreigner Looks at the New Life Movement," T'ien Hsia Monthly, printed copy, 8 pages, undated
    - "The Future of Shanghai," The China Critic, printed copy, 2 pages, 1938 January 27
    - "Glimpses Across the Pacific," The China Critic, printed copy, 2 pages, 1935 December 12
    - "Gould Comes Through with 'Scoop,'" The Shanghai Spectator, printed copy, 1 page, 1933 February 23
    - "If You Fight You May Get Hit," unpublished report, carbon of typewritten manuscript and photocopy, 68 pages, 1949
    - "Madame Sun Yat-sen Keeps Faith," The Nation, printed copy, 2 pages, undated
    - "Mayor Wu and Shanghai," The China Critic, printed copy, 2 pages, 1937 April 8
    - Memo on references of Randall Gould, 2 typewritten copies, 3 pages, 1950
    - "Newspapers in China," The Chinese Nation, 2 printed copies, 2 pages, 1930 June 18
    - "An Open Letter to Lin Yutang," The China Critic, printed copy, 3 pages, 1935 December 19
      With clipping of newspaper reply from Lin Yutang.
    - "An Open Letter to Our Readers," carbon of editorial, 1 page, undated
    - "Planned, Not Pork-Barrel, Expenditure," The China Critic, printed copy, 2 pages, 1933 October 5
    - "Private Enterprise in Postwar China," China Trade News, printed copy, 3 pages, 1945 January
    - "Recruits Drifting in Add to China Staffs, Editor & Publisher, printed copy, 1 page, 1937 October 16
    - "Shanghai's Economic Anxieties," The China Critic, printed copy, 2 pages, 1938 May 5
    - "Sian Background," printed copy, 2 pages, undated
    - "A Trip to the War Zone," The Chinese Nation, printed copy, 3 pages, 1930 July 16
    - "What Happens to Press When Commies Come," Editor & Publisher, printed copy, 1 page, 1951 January 6
    - "When the Reds Came," Pen, printed copy, 4 pages, 1955 January
    - "Why Yenching Has Succeeded," Peking News, printed copy, 2 pages, 1927 June 22
  - Untitled drafts and articles
    - 1927
    - 1949-1953
    - Miscellaneous, undated
- Scrapbooks, 1937-1938 (Boxes 7-9)
  Newspaper clippings, primarily of the bombing of Shanghai, China, in three scrapbooks.
- Photographs, 1937-1945, undated
  - 2 prints of George Gould; 1 print of George Gould and others, 1 print of Mr. and Mrs. George Gould and Randall Gould, 4 prints of Randall Gould, 6 prints of Randall Gould and others, 2 prints of the Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury building, 7 miscellaneous prints, undated (Envelope A)
  - 5 albums of prints of the Japanese bombing of Shanghai, China, 1937 (Album fB-F)
  - 16 prints depicting the execution of Chinese civilians by Japanese soldiers during the Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945 (Envelope G)
  - 1 album of prints of the Japanese bombing of Shanghai, 1937 (Album fH)